Falguni Mittal

Matawan, NJ

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Falguni-Mittal/b7483a9cb4858807

Business Systems Analyst with a background in Project Management and Technology development with additional skills in Advanced Excel, VBA, Python and SQL from Rutgers Data Science Bootcamp. Enjoys leveraging experience and skills set to support detailed and efficient analysis to discover insights.

Strengths include understanding and analyzing business problems and translating them into design specs combined with collaborating with diverse groups.

Work Experience

Sr. Business Systems Analyst/Agile Product Owner

Education Testing Services - Princeton, NJ July 2016 to August 2021

Development of app-based test delivery product for federal testing program.

Data validation of assessments for various Educator Licensure, English Language Learning, and K-12 Student Programs.

Key Accomplishments:

- Analysis of data with complex rules and scoring data models, documentation of business and functional requirements, support development and testing, plan and track project milestone dates, estimate project budget.
- Managed product requirements for a new lightweight app used for test administration, including API development, and version control of software from download center.
- Coordination with scrum teams to plan and develop product releases, including creating user stories in Jira, sprint planning, managing backlog, and sprint demo.
- Review current processes and document current and future workflows
- Established a Help Desk for the current assessment year to report and resolve technical issues, including Zendesk ticketing system workflows, management of KBAs, training for help desk staff.
- Maintenance of performance Dashboard

Sr. Business Systems Analyst

Horizon BCBS of New Jersey - Newark, NJ April 2015 to November 2015

Development of new product - Medical Cost Reduction project which offers cardiac behavioral health intervention program to eligible members to improve quality of care.

Key Accomplishments:

- Create business case for the new product by partnering with business owner
- Identify and document key business and functional requirements for the project by working with multidisciplinary teams.

Enterprise Business Systems Analyst

Healthfirst - New York, NY August 2013 to April 2015 Build products and services at health care insurance company to serve individuals, family, and small businesses.

- Duties included documenting project scope specifications, conduct stakeholder interviews, facilitate JAD sessions, requirements analysis and documentation of business and functional requirements
- Data analysis using SAS front-end tool, Support Development, UAT and deployment Key Accomplishments:
- Explanation of Benefits (EOB) for Medicare Advantage plan members.
- Reengineer Enrollment processes for Medicare and Medicaid lines of business..

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

New Jersey Institute of Technology - Newark, NJ

Certificate

Rutgers University - Newark, NJ

Skills

- Business Intelligence Tools Tableau (link to projects)
- MS Power BI
- Jira
- Confluence
- Gliffy
- MS Project
- Visio
- Excel
- VBA
- Python
- SQL
- MS SQL Server
- GitHub
- SDLC
- AWS
- Agile
- Waterfall
- DevOps

Links

http://www.linkedin.com/in.falguni-mittal-pmp-csm-37206359

Certifications and Licenses

PMP

PMI Certification

Certified Scrum Master